<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<info>
    <item id="txt_pres_mmw">
        <![CDATA[<b>millimeter of water</b> (mmH2O, mm WC, mm CE, mm WS) a unit of
pressure equal to the pressure exerted at the Earth's surface by a
column of water 1 millimeter high. This is a small pressure, about
9.8067 pascals, 0.098 067 millibars, 0.03937 inch of water, or 0.204
pounds per square foot. The French symbol is mm CE (colonne d'eau), and
the German symbol is mm WS (Wassersäule).

[Source: <a href="http://geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictM.html#mm_WC">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictM.html</a>]
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="helptext">
        <![CDATA[<b>Enter a value into the textfield of that unit you want to
            convert.<br/>The converted values will be displayed in the other
            textfields while you type.</b>
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="special_txt_dist_feetin">
        <![CDATA[<font color=#2945ab><b>Enter feet and inches in the following format
                (example): 22'-8" - or: 22-8<br>which results in: 22 feet and
                    8 inches</b></font>
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="txt_pres_pa">
        <![CDATA[<b>the SI unit of pressure.</b> The pascal is the standard pressure
unit in the MKS metric system, equal to one newton per square meter or
one "kilogram per meter per second per second." Sounds impressive,
but in traditional English terms a pascal is only 0.000 145 pounds per
square inch (0.020 885 lbf/ft2 or 0.007 50 mmHg). Thus pressure is more
commonly measured in kilopascals (kPa), with 1 kPa = 0.145 lbf/in2. Air
pressure is measured in hectopascals (hPa), with 1 hPa = 1 millibar.
The unit is named for Blaise Pascal (1623-1662), French philosopher and
mathematician, who was the first person to use a barometer to measure
differences in altitude. See Pressure.

[Source: <a href="http://www.geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictP.html#pascal">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictP.html#pascal</a>]
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="txt_pres_inwg">
        <![CDATA[<b>inch of water gauge</b> (in wg or "wg) another common name for the inch of
water column. The word "gauge" (or "gage") after a pressure reading
indicates that the pressure stated is actually the difference between the
absolute, or total, pressure and the air pressure at the time of the reading.
[Source: <a href="http://www.geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictI.html">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictI.html</a>]

        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="txt_pres_atm">
        <![CDATA[<b>atmosphere (atm or atmos)</b> a unit of pressure designed to equal the
average pressure of the Earth's atmosphere at sea level. In other pressure
units, one atmosphere equals exactly 1013.25 millibars (mb), 101.325
kilopascals (kPa), approximately 29.92 inches of mercury (in Hg), or 14.6959
pounds of force per square inch (lb/in2). See Converter. This is the standard
atmosphere; it equals 1.0332 technical atmosphere.

[Source: <a href="http://www.geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictA.html">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictA.html</a>]
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="txt_pres_bar">
        <![CDATA[<b>bar (b)</b> A metric unit of atmospheric pressure, equal to one million
dynes per square centimeter, 100 kilopascals, 750.062 torr, 1.01972 kilograms
of force per square centimeter (kgf/cm2), or about 14.50378 pounds per square
inch (lbf/in2). See Converter.
<br />
The word comes from the Greek baros,
"weighty". We see the same root in our word, barometer, for an instrument
measuring atmospheric pressure. One bar is just a bit less than the average
pressure of the Earth's atmosphere, which is 1.013 25 bar. In practice,
meteorologists generally record atmospheric pressure in millibars (mb). In
English-speaking countries, barometric pressure is also expressed as the
height, in inches, of a column of mercury supported by the pressure of the
atmosphere. In this unit, one bar equals 29.53 inches of mercury (in Hg).

[Source: <a href="http://www.geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictB.html#bar">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictB.html</a>]
        ]]>
    </item>
    <item id="txt_pres_psi">
        <![CDATA[<b>pound per square inch</b> (lbf/in 2 or psi)a traditional unit of pressure. 1
psi equals 144 pounds per square foot (psf), 6.894 75 kilopascals (kPa),
68.9475 millibars (mb), 2.036 inches of mercury (inHg), or 27.7612 inches of
water (inWC). See below for related notations such as "psig".

[Source: <a href="http://www.geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictP.html">geocities.com/jayatea.geo/dictP.html</a>]
        ]]>
    </item>
</info>
