<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!--
Convert Setup XML File
Version: 1.0.0

Simon A. Wilper/Uwe Eschenhorst
2014-12-26 - Update
2013-03-31 - Consolidation of all settings in one XML configuration
2006-08-23 - Initial Edit

The first unit should be the SI Unit of that particular group and is
represented by factor 1.  All factors of the subsequent units if
multiplied by will result in the SI Unit.

Use the transform attribute to perform more complex transformation of
the values.
-->
<units>
  <group id="vol" label="Volumes" icon=":/icon/icons/volume.png">
    <unit id="qubicmetre" label="Qubic Metre [m^3]" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The cubic metre (US spelling: cubic meter, symbol: m<sup>3</sup>)
        is the SI derived unit of volume. It is the volume of a cube
        with edges one metre in length. An alternative name, which
        allowed a different usage with metric prefixes, was the stère.
        Another alternative name, not widely used any more, is the
        kilolitre. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cubic_metre">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="liter" label="Litre [l] or [dm^3]" type="factor" value=".001">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The litre (American spelling: liter; SI symbols l or
        L[1]) is a non-SI metric system unit of volume equal to 1 cubic
        decimetre (dm3), 1,000 cubic centimetres (cm3) or 1/1,000 cubic
        metre. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Litre">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="cubicfoot" label="Cubic Foot [cft or ft^3]" type="factor" value=".02831685">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The term cubic foot is an Imperial and US customary (non-metric) unit of 
		volume, used in the United States and the United Kingdom. It is defined as the volume 
		of a cube with sides of one foot (0.3048 m) in length. Its volume is 28.3168 liters or
		about one 35th (1/35.3147248277) of a cubic meter. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cubic_foot">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  <unit id="cubicinch" label="Cubic Inch [cin or inch^3]" type="factor" value=".00001638706">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[]]>
      </info>
    </unit>

  <unit id="registerton" label="Register Ton [rt]" type="factor" value="2.831685">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The register ton is a unit of volume used to express the capacity of a ship.
		For example, a 20 000 ton freighter has a capacity of approximately 57 000 m<sup>3</sup>,
		measured in accordance with established procedures.]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
<unit id="bushel" label="Bushel [bsh or bu]" type="factor" value="0.03523907">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Agricultural products that are sold by the bushel in the United States are 
		often sold by weight in other countries. There can be a considerable variation in the 
		weight per unit volume due to differences in variety, size, or condition of the commodity, 
		tightness of pack, degree to which the container is heaped, etc. The following conversion 
		factors are used by the U.S. Department of Agriculture for statistical purposes:
		<br>
		barley = 21.9 kg per bushel<br>
		corn, shelled = 25.4 kg per bushel<br>
		oats = 14.5 kg per bushel<br>
		potatoes, soybeans, wheat = 27.2 kg per bushel]]>
      </info>
    </unit>

<unit id="fluidounce" label="Fluid Ounce (US) [fl. oz.]" type="factor" value=".00002957353">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[In the United States, the cup, tablespoon, and teaspoon are defined as 8, 1/2, and 1/6
		fluid ounces, respectively. for pratical usage the metric equivalents are 250 mL, 15 mL, and 5 mL.]]>
      </info>
    </unit>	
	
<unit id="quart" label="Quart (liquid) [qr]" type="factor" value=".0009463529">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The quart is a unit of volume (for either the imperial or United States 
		customary units) equal to a quarter of a gallon (hence the name quart), two pints, 
		or four cups. Since gallons of various sizes have historically been in use, quarts 
		of various sizes have also existed; see gallon for further discussion. Three of these 
		kinds of quarts remain in current use, all approximately equal to one litre. Its proper 
		abbreviation is qt. Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quart">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
	
	
    <unit id="milliliter" label="Millilitre [ml]" type="factor" value=".000001">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see Litre (milli = 10^-3)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="gallon" label="Gallon [gal]" type="factor" value=".003785412">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The gallon (abbreviation "gal"), is a measure of volume
        that was used in many parts of Western Europe and is still used
        in the United States. Historically its value differed depending
        on locality and commodity. In most localities it has been
        replaced by the litre, but three variants in current use: the
        imperial gallon (≈ 4.546 L) which since metrication is used
        colloquially in the United Kingdom and semi-officially within
        Canada, the United States (liquid) gallon (≈ 3.79 L), and the
        lesser used US dry gallon (≈ 4.40 L). The gallon, be it the
        imperial or US gallon, is sometimes found in other
        English-speaking countries. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gallon">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="pint" label="Pint [pt]" type="factor" value=".0004731765">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The pint (abbreviated as "pt" or "p") is a unit of
        volume or capacity that was once used across much of Europe with
        values varying between countries from less than half a litre to
        over one litre. Within continental Europe, the pint was replaced
        with the metric system during the nineteenth century. However,
        in the United States, the United Kingdom, and various other
        Commonwealth countries, the unit has continued to be in use.
        There is also limited use of the term in parts of France, Quebec
        ("une pinte") and Central Europe, notably some areas in Germany
        and Switzerland. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pint">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <group id="powers" label="Powers" icon=":/icon/icons/power.png">
    <unit id="w" label="Watt [W]" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The watt (pron.: /ˈwɒt/ WOT; symbol: W) is a derived
        unit of power in the International System of Units (SI), named
        after the Scottish engineer James Watt (1736–1819). The unit,
        defined as one joule per second, measures the rate of energy
        conversion or transfer. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Watt">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="w" label="Kilo-Watt [kW]" type="factor" value="1000"></unit>	
    <unit id="hp" label="Horsepower (metric) [HP]" type="factor" value="735.49875">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Horsepower (hp) is the name of several units of
        measurement of power, the rate at which work is done.  The most
        common conversion factor, especially for electrical power, is 1
        hp = 746 watts. The term was adopted in the late 18th century by
        Scottish engineer James Watt to compare the output of steam
        engines with the power of draft horses. It was later expanded to
        include the output power of other types of piston engines, as
        well as turbines, electric motors and other machinery.[1][2] The
        definition of the unit varied between geographical regions. Most
        countries now use the SI unit watt for measurement of power.
        With the implementation of the EU Directive 80/181/EEC on
        January 1, 2010, the use of horsepower in the EU is only
        permitted as supplementary unit. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horsepower">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="hp" label="Horsepower (imperial mechanical) [HP]" type="factor" value="745.69987158227022">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Horsepower (hp) imperial mechanical. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Horsepower">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>	
  </group>

  <group id="forces" label="Forces" icon=":/icon/icons/force.png">
    <unit id="n" label="Newton" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The newton (symbol: N) is the International System of
        Units (SI) derived unit of force. It is named after Isaac Newton
        in recognition of his work on classical mechanics, specifically
        Newton's second law of motion. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newton_%28unit%29">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="dyne" label="Dyne" type="factor" value="1e-5">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[In physics, the dyne (symbol "dyn", from Greek δύναμις
        (dynamis) meaning power, force) is a unit of force specified in
        the centimetre-gram-second (CGS) system of units, a predecessor
        of the modern SI. One dyne is equal to 10 µN (micronewtons).
        Equivalently, the dyne is defined as "the force required to
        accelerate a mass of one gram at a rate of one centimetre per
        second squared" Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dyne">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <!-- lengths/distance - relative to base SI unit m (meter) -->
  <group id="len" label="Distance" icon=":/icon/icons/cursor.png">
    <unit id="meter" label="Meter [m]" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The metre (meter in American English), (SI unit symbol:
        m; SI dimension symbol: L), is the fundamental unit of length in
        the International System of Units (SI).[1] Originally intended
        to be one ten-millionth of the distance from the Earth's equator
        to the North Pole (at sea level), its definition has been
        periodically refined to reflect growing knowledge of
        metrology. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meter">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="centimeter" label="Centimeter [cm]" type="factor" value=".01">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see metre (1m = 100cm)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="millimeter" label="Millimeter [mm]" type="factor" value=".001">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see metre (1m = 1000mm)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="kilometer" label="Kilometer [km]" type="factor" value="1e+3">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see metre (1km = 1000m)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="foot" label="Foot [ft]" type="factor" value=".3048006">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A foot (plural: feet; abbreviation or symbol: ft or ′
        (the prime symbol) is a unit of length defined as being 0.3048 m
        exactly and used in the imperial system of units and United
        States customary units. It is subdivided into 12 inches. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foot_%28unit%29">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="inch" label="Inch [in]" type="factor" value=".0254">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[An inch (plural: inches; abbreviation or symbol: in or
        ″ – a double prime) is a unit of length in a number of systems
        of measurement, including the imperial and United States
        customary systems. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inch">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="feet_inches" label="Feet-Inches [ft-in]" type="formatted" value=".0254"
      inputpattern="(\d+)-(\d+)" outputpattern="%1ft - %2in">
      <subunits>
        <subunit value="12" />
      </subunits>
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Enter a formatted feet-inch length, e.g. 2-42 (2 feet,
        42 inches)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
	<unit id="mile" label="Mile [mi]" type="factor" value="1609.344">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A mile is a unit of length most commonly equivalent to
        5,280 feet (1,760 yards, or about 1,609 metres). Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mile">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="yard" label="Yard [yd]" type="factor" value=".9144">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A yard (abbreviation: yd) is a unit of length in the imperial 
		and United States customary systems of measurement. Historically a yard was 
		also used in other systems of units. The yard is equal to 3 feet or 36 inches. 
		Under an agreement in 1959 between Australia, Canada, New Zealand, South Africa, 
		the United Kingdom and the United States, the yard (known as the "international yard" 
		in the United States) was legally defined to be exactly 0.9144 metres. Prior to 
		that date, the legal definition of the yard when expressed in terms of metric units 
		varied slightly from country to country. Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yard">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>	
	</unit>
	</group>

  <group id="alen" label="Astronomical Lenghts" icon=":icon/icons/planets.png">
    <unit id="pc" label="Parsec" type="factor" value="30.856776e+15">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The parsec (symbol: pc) is a unit of length used in astronomy,
        equal to about 30.9 trillion kilometres (19.2 trillion miles) or 3.26
        light-years. The name parsec is "an abbreviated form of 'a distance
        corresponding to a parallax of one arcsecond'."[1] It was coined in
        1913 at the suggestion of British astronomer Herbert Hall Turner. A
        parsec is the distance from the Sun to an astronomical object which has
        a parallax angle of one arcsecond (1⁄3,600 of a degree).
        Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parsec">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="ae" label="Astronomical Unit" type="factor" value="149597870700">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[An astronomical unit (abbreviated as au;[1] other
        abbreviations that are sometimes used include a.u. and ua[2]) is a
        unit of length now defined as exactly 149,597,870,700 m (92,955,807.3
        mi),[3] or roughly the mean Earth–Sun distance.
        Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Astronomical_unit">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="ly" label="Lightyear" type="factor" value="9.461e+15">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A light-year, also light year or lightyear (symbol: ly), is an
        astronomical unit of length equal to just under 10 trillion kilometres
        (or about 6 trillion miles).[note 1] As defined by the International
        Astronomical Union (IAU), a light-year is the distance that light
        travels in a vacuum in one Julian year.[1]
        Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightyear">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <!-- temperature - relative to base SI unit K (Kelvin) -->
  <group id="temp" label="Temperatures" icon=":icon/icons/temperature.png">
    <unit id="kelvin" label="Kelvin [K]" type="transform" toSI="x * 1" fromSI="x * 1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The kelvin is a unit of measurement for temperature. It is one
        of the seven base units in the International System of Units (SI) and
        is assigned the unit symbol K. The Kelvin scale is an absolute,
        thermodynamic temperature scale using as its null point absolute zero,
        the temperature at which all thermal motion ceases in the classical
        description of thermodynamics. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kelvin">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="celsius" label="Celsius [°C]" type="transform" toSI="x - 273.15" fromSI="x + 273.15">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Celsius, also known as centigrade,[1] is a scale and unit of
        measurement for temperature. It is named after the Swedish astronomer
        Anders Celsius (1701–1744), who developed a similar temperature scale.
        The degree Celsius (°C) can refer to a specific temperature on the
        Celsius scale as well as a unit to indicate a temperature interval, a
        difference between two temperatures or an uncertainty. The unit was
        known until 1948 as "centigrade" from the Latin centum translated as
        100 and gradus translated as "steps". Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Celsius">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="fahrenheit" label="Fahrenheit [°F]" type="transform" toSI="(9/5*(x-273.15)+32)" fromSI="5/9*(x - 32)+273.15">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Fahrenheit (symbol °F) is a temperature scale based on one
        proposed in 1724 by the physicist Daniel Gabriel Fahrenheit
        (1686–1736), after whom the scale is named.[1] Within this scale, the
        freezing of water into ice is defined at 32 degrees, while the boiling
        point of water is defined to be 212 degrees—on Fahrenheit's original
        scale the freezing point of brine was zero degrees. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fahrenheit">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="rankine" label="Rankine [°R]" type="transform" toSI="x * 1.8" fromSI="x / 1.8">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Rankine is a thermodynamic (absolute) temperature scale named
        after the Glasgow University engineer and physicist William John
        Macquorn Rankine, who proposed it in 1859. (The Kelvin scale was first
        proposed in 1848.) Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rankine_scale">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <!-- pressure - relative to base SI unit kPa (Kilopascal) -->
  <group id="pres" label="Pressures" icon=":icon/icons/arrow_down.png">
    <unit id="kpa" label="Kilopascal [kPa]" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The pascal (symbol: Pa) is the SI derived unit of pressure,
        internal pressure, stress, Young's modulus and tensile strength,[1]
        named after the French mathematician, physicist, inventor, writer, and
        philosopher Blaise Pascal. It is a measure of force per unit area,
        defined as one newton per square meter.  Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kilopascal">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="pa" label="Pascal [Pa]" type="factor" value=".001">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see Kilopascal (1kPa = 1000Pa)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="inwg" label="Inch Water Gauge [inch WG]" type="factor" value=".24884">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Inches of water, wc, inch water column (inch WC), inAq, Aq, or
        inH2O is a non-SI unit for pressure. The units are by convention and
        due to the historical measurement of certain pressure differentials. It
        is used for measuring small pressure differences across an orifice, or
        in a pipeline or shaft.[1] Inches of water can be converted to a
        pressure unit using the formula for pressure head. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inch_of_water">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="mmw" label="Millimeter of Water [mm H2O]" type="factor" value="0.009804">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[mmWG is widely used in industrial descriptions and many of
        technical specifications as the unit of pressure or pressure drop.
        mm.Wg means millimeters, water gauge. It is the pressure required to
        support a water column of the specified height (sometimes called 'head'
        of water). Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millimeters,_water_gauge">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="atm" label="Atmosphere [atm]" type="factor" value="101.325">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The standard atmosphere (symbol: atm) is an international
        reference pressure defined as 101325 Pa and formerly used as a unit of
        pressure.[1] For practical purposes it has been replaced by the bar
        which is 100 kPa.[1] The difference of about 1% is not significant for
        many applications, and is within the error range of common pressure
        gauges. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmosphere_%28unit%29">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="bar" label="Bar [bar]" type="factor" value="100">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The bar is a non-SI unit of pressure, defined by the IUPAC as
        exactly equal to 100,000 Pa.[1] It is about equal to the atmospheric
        pressure on Earth at sea level, and since 1982 the IUPAC has
        recommended that the standard for atmospheric pressure should be
        harmonized to 100,000 Pa = 1 bar ≈ 750.0616827 Torr. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bar_%28unit%29">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="mbar" label="Millibar [mm bar] or [hPa]" type="factor" value=".1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see Bar (1bar = 1000mbar)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="psi" label="PSI [psi]" type="factor" value="6.894757">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The pound per square inch or, more accurately, pound-force per
        square inch (symbol: psi or lbf/in2 or lbf/in2 or lbf/sq in or lbf/sq
        in)/ pressure per square inch is a unit of pressure or of stress based
        on avoirdupois units. It is the pressure resulting from a force of one
        pound-force applied to an area of one square inch Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pounds_per_square_inch">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="inchhg" label="Inch of Mercury [inHg]" type="factor" value="3.386389">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[ Inches of mercury, (inHg and "Hg) is a unit of measurement for pressure. 
		It is still used for barometric pressure in weather reports, refrigeration and aviation 
		in the United States. It is defined as the pressure exerted by a circular column of
		mercury of 1 inch in height at 32 °F (0 °C) at the standard acceleration of gravity.
		Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inch_of_mercury">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
   <unit id="mmhg" label="Millimeter of Mercury [mm Hg]" type="factor" value=".1333224">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[ A millimeter of mercury is a manometric unit of pressure, formerly defined as 
		the extra pressure generated by a column of mercury one millimetre high. It is now defined 
		precisely as 13.5951 × 9.80665 = 133.322387415 pascals.[1] It is denoted by the symbol "mmHg".
		Although not an SI unit, the millimeter of mercury is still routinely used in medicine, 
		meteorology and many other scientific fields.
		One millimeter of mercury is approximately 1 Torr, or 1/760 of standard atmospheric pressure. The two units are not exactly equal; however, the difference (less than 0.000015%) is negligible for most practical uses.
		Source: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Millimeter_of_mercury">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
   </group>

  <!-- areas - relative to base SI unit square km -->
  <group id="area" label="Areas" icon=":icon/icons/rect.png">
    <unit id="squaremeter" label="Square_meter" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The square metre (British spelling) or square meter (American
        spelling) is the SI derived unit of area, with symbol m2 (33A1 in
        Unicode[1]). It is defined as the area of a square whose sides measure
        exactly one metre. The square metre is derived from the SI base unit of
        the metre, which itself is defined as the length of the path travelled
        by light in absolute vacuum during a time interval of 1/299,792,458 of
        a second. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_meter">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="squarekm" label="Square_kilometer" type="factor" value="1e+6">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see square meter (1square kilometer = 1e+6square meter)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="acre" label="_Acre" type="factor" value="4046.9">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The acre is a unit of area used in the imperial and U.S.
        customary systems. An acre is about 40% of a hectare – slightly smaller
        than an American football field. The acre is no longer commonly used in
        most countries, although a few notable exceptions include the United
        States, Australia, India, Burma and the United Kingdom (as of 2010, the
        acre is no longer officially used in the United Kingdom, though is
        still used in real estate descriptions). It is still used, to some
        extent, in Canada. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Acre">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="squareinch" label="Square_inch" type="factor" value=".00064516">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A square inch (plural: square inches) is a unit of area, equal
        to the area of a square with sides of one inch. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_inch">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="squarefoot" label="Square_foot" type="factor" value=".09290304">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The square foot (plural square feet; abbreviated ft² or sq ft)
        is an imperial unit and U.S. customary unit (non-SI non-metric) of
        area, used mainly in the United States, Canada, United Kingdom, Hong
        Kong[citation needed], Bangladesh, India, Pakistan and
        Afghanistan[citation needed]. It is defined as the area of a square
        with sides of 1 foot (0.333... yards, 12 inches, or 0.3048 metres) in
        length. For comparison, the average new one-family house in the United
        States in 2007 had a total floor area of approximately 2500 square feet
        (232 square meters). Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_foot">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="hectare" label="_Hectare" type="factor" value="10000">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The hectare (/ˈhɛktɛər/ or /ˈhɛktɑr/; symbol ha) is a metric
        unit of area defined as 10,000 square metres (100 m by 100 m), and
        primarily used in the measurement of land. In 1795, when the metric
        system was introduced, the 'are' was defined as 100 square metres and
        the hectare ('hecto-' + 'are') was thus 100 'ares' or 1/100 km2. A
        hectare of land is about 2.471 acres. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hectare">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="squareyard" label="Square_yard" type="factor" value=".8361274">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The square yard is an imperial/US customary (non-metric) unit
        of area, formerly used in most of the English-speaking world but now
        generally replaced by the square metre outside of the U.S., Canada and
        the U.K. It is defined as the area of a square with sides of one yard
        (three feet, thirty-six inches, 0.9144 metres) in length. (Gaj in
        Hindi) Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_yard">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="squaremile" label="Squa_remile" type="factor" value="2589988">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The square mile (abbreviated as sq mi and sometimes as mi2)[1]
        is an imperial and US unit of measure for an area equal to the area of
        a square of one statute mile.[2] It should not be confused with miles
        square, which refers to the number of miles on each side squared. For
        instance, 20 miles square (20 × 20 miles) is equal to 400 square miles;
        an area of 10 × 40 miles is likewise 400 square miles, but it is not 20
        miles square. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Square_mile">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <group id="mom" label="Momentum of Intertia" icon=":icon/icons/inertia.png">
    <unit id="kgmsquared" label="_Kilogram Meter Squared" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="poundsquarefoot" label="_Pound Square Foot" type="factor" value=".04214011">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <!-- mass - relative to base SI unit kg -->
  <group id="mass" label="Masses" icon=":icon/icons/weight.png">
    <unit id="kg" label="Kilogram" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The kilogram or kilogramme (SI unit symbol: kg; SI dimension
        symbol: M), is the base unit of mass in the International System of
        Units and is defined as being equal to the mass of the International
        Prototype of the Kilogram (IPK).[2] The avoirdupois (or international)
        pound, used in both the Imperial system and U.S. customary units, is
        defined as exactly 0.45359237 kg, making one kilogram approximately
        equal to 2.2046 avoirdupois pounds. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kilogram">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="gram" label="Gram" type="factor" value=".001">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see kilogram (1kg=1000g)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="tonmetric" label="Metric Ton" type="factor" value="1000">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[see kilogram (1t=1000kg)]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="pound" label="Pound" type="factor" value=".45359237">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The pound or pound-mass (abbreviations: lb, lbm, lbm, ℔[1]) is
        a unit of mass used in the imperial, United States customary and other
        systems of measurement. A number of different definitions have been
        used, the most common today being the international avoirdupois pound
        which is legally defined as exactly 0.45359237 kilograms. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pound_%28mass%29">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="tonshort" label="Short Ton" type="factor" value="907.18474">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The short ton is a unit of mass equal to 2,000 pounds
        (907.18474 kg), that is most commonly used in the United States – known
        there simply as the ton. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Short_ton">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="grain" label="Grain" type="factor" value="64.798e-6">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A grain is a unit of measurement of mass that is nominally
        based upon the mass of a single seed of a cereal. From the Bronze Age
        into the Renaissance the average masses of wheat and barley grains were
        part of the legal definition of units of mass. However, there is no
        evidence of any country ever having used actual seeds or cereal grains.
        Rather, expressions such as "thirty-two grains of wheat, taken from the
        middle of the ear" appear to have been ritualistic formulas,
        essentially the premodern equivalent of legal boilerplate. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grain_%28unit%29">Wikipedia</a>
        ]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="tonlong" label="Long Ton" type="factor" value="1016.047">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Long ton (weight ton or Imperial ton) is the name for the unit
        called the "ton" in the avoirdupois or Imperial system of measurements
        that was used in the United Kingdom and several other Commonwealth
        countries before metrication. One long ton is equal to 2,240 pounds
        (1,016 kg), 1.12 times as much as a short ton and slightly (1.59%)
        larger than the 1,000 kilograms (2,205 lb) metric tonne, or 35 cubic
        feet (0.9911 m3) of salt water with a density of 64 lb/cu ft (1.025
        g/ml).[1] It has some limited use in the United States, most commonly
        in measuring the displacement of ships, and was the unit prescribed for
        warships by the Washington Naval Treaty 1922—for example battleships
        were limited to a mass of 35,000 long tons (36,000 t; 39,000 short
        tons). Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long_ton">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="ouncetroy" label="Ounce Troy" type="factor" value="31.10348e-3">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The troy ounce (oz t) is a unit of imperial measure. In the
        present day it is most commonly used to gauge the mass of precious
        metals. One troy ounce is currently defined as exactly 0.0311034768 kg
        or 31.1034768 g. There are approximately 32.15 troy oz in 1 kg. One
        troy ounce is equivalent to approximately 1.09714 avoirdupois ounces.
        Source <a href="">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="ounceav" label="Ounce Av" type="factor" value="28.34952e-3">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The avoirdupois ounce is the most commonly used ounce today.
        It is defined to be one sixteenth of an avoirdupois pound. The
        avoirdupois pound is defined as 7000 grains; one ounce is therefore
        equal to 437.5 grains. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Avoirdupois_ounce#International_avoirdupois_ounce">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <group id="times" label="Times" icon=":icon/icons/time.png">
    <unit id="s" label="Second" type="factor" value="1">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The second (symbol: s) is the base unit of time in the
        International System of Units (SI)[1] and is also a unit of time in
        other systems of measurement (abbreviated s or sec;[2]) it is the
        second division of the hour by sixty, the first division by 60 being
        the minute.[3] Between 1000 (when al-Biruni used seconds) and 1960 the
        second was defined as 1/86,400 of a mean solar day (that definition
        still applies in some astronomical and legal contexts).[4][5] Between
        1960 and 1967, it was defined in terms of the period of the Earth's
        orbit around the Sun in 1900,[6] but it is now defined more precisely
        in atomic terms. Seconds may be measured using mechanical, electric or
        atomic clocks. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="min" label="Minute" type="factor" value="60">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[A minute is a unit of measurement of time or of angle. The
        minute is a unit of time equal to 1⁄60 (the first sexagesimal
        fraction[1]) of an hour or 60 seconds. In the UTC time standard, a
        minute on rare occasions has 59 or 61 seconds, a consequence of leap
        seconds. Although not an SI unit, the minute is accepted for use with
        SI units.[2] The SI symbol for minute or minutes is min (for time
        measurement) or the prime symbol after a number, e.g. 5′ (for angle
        measurement, even if it is informally used for time). Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minute">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="h" label="Hour" type="factor" value="3600">
      <info>
        <![CDATA[The hour (common symbol: h or hr) is a unit of measurement of
        time. In modern usage, an hour comprises 60 minutes, or 3,600 seconds.
        It is approximately 1/24 of a mean solar day. Source: <a
          href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hour">Wikipedia</a>]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
    <unit id="hms" label="h:m:s" type="formatted" value="1"
      inputpattern="(\d+):(\d+):(\d+)" outputpattern="%1h %2m %3s">
      <subunits>
        <subunit value="3600" />
        <subunit value="60" />
      </subunits>
      <info>
        <![CDATA[Enter a formatted time string, e.g. 1:42:23 for 1 hour,
        42 minutes, 23 seconds]]>
      </info>
    </unit>
  </group>

  <group id="" label="Mass Flows" icon=":icon/icons/weight.png">
    <unit id="kgpersecond" label="Kilograms per Second" type="transform"
      toSI="x" fromSI="x"/>
    <unit id="kgperminute" label="Kilograms per Minute" type="transform"
      toSI="x * 60" fromSI="x / 60"/>
    <unit id="kgperhour" label="Kilograms per Hour" type="transform"
      toSI="x * 3600" fromSI="x / 3600"/>
    <unit id="lbpersecond" label="Pound per Second" type="transform"
      toSI="x * 2.20462262" fromSI="x / 2.20462262"/>
    <unit id="lbperminute" label="Pound per Minute" type="transform"
      toSI="x * 2.20462262 * 60" fromSI="x / 2.20462262 / 60"/>
    <unit id="lbperhour" label="Pound per Hour" type="transform"
      toSI="x * 2.20462262 * 60 * 60" fromSI="x / 2.20462262 / 60 / 60"/>
  </group>

</units>
